Tatiana Didik

- linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tatianadidik hackerrank: https://www.hackerrank.com/aquarellian •
- stakoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/7111382/tatiana-didik github: https://github.com/aguarellian •
- e-mail: tatiana.didik.0@gmail.com US Visa Status: GC Current Location: Weehawken, NJ (NYC Area) •

Software Engineer

A passionate back-end developer, a team-worker, who undertakes complex assignments, meets tight deadlines and delivers great performance. Result- and quality-oriented specialist, open to new technologies and business challenges. Experienced in all phases of a project from initial development to production support, including monitoring and resolution of performance related issues. Oracle Certified Java Programmer II (Professional).

Core Competencies

\checkmark	Java	\checkmark	Maven	\checkmark	Hibernate	\checkmark	Jenkins	✓	HTML
\checkmark	Python	✓	Gradle	\checkmark	JDBC	\checkmark	GitLab	\checkmark	CSS
✓	ShellScript	\checkmark	Linux	\checkmark	Git	\checkmark	TeamCity	\checkmark	UML
✓	SQL	✓	Vagrant	\checkmark	SVN	\checkmark	JIRA	\checkmark	JavScript
✓	XMI	✓	JBoss	✓	SonarQube	✓	JProfiler	✓	Gerrit

Certifications

Oracle Certified Associate	Java SE 7 Programmer I	90%	<u>January 2015</u>
Oracle Certified Professional	Java SE 7 Programmer II	86%	February 2015

Professional Experience

BJSS INC / Senior Developer Consultant / Full Time

Apr 2018 - Current

BJSS is an award-winning(Queen's Award for Enterprise) delivery focusing IT consultancy

Financial Industry Client / Active Trading

Jul 2018 - Current

- ✓ Automated performance analysis of several high load applications with customized tools written from scratch on Python, utilizing Pandas and Matplotlib libraries. The tools are used routinely for baseline tests performance analysis for all major releases and are visualizing latency and throughput metrics. Created and maintained Kibana Dashboards with Timelion visualizations, allowing to get live performance data from production system.
- ✓ Developed configurable instrumentation implementation for a custom thread pool framework allowing to locate performance flaws in the thread pool itself as well as in external code utilizing it. Automated instrumentation and execution latency analysis with Python and Kibana visualization, allowing to track performance issues down to a code line location and correlate performance recessions with GC events. Using the instrumentation and analysis tools, detected and fixed a performance issue, resulting in 5 times latency improvement in 99 percentile, 3 times in average and allowing to increase throughput by 10% in the affected module.
- ✓ Utilized Cucumber and Spock with PowerMock in a Gradle project to create unit, functional and integration testing frameworks for message driven module and for thread pool implementation. Refactored an overly complicated multi-threaded module, allowing easily support and maintain the code, providing clear visibility of context switches.
- ✓ Created a tool for parsing and comparison of BIOS and network settings printouts from 100+ servers, allowing
 to find and fix inconsistencies. Applied various BIOS configurations using Conrep tool and executed
 performance tests allowing to determine gains and hazards of use of various BIOS settings and network
 interfaces of higher capacities. Verified update of unified BIOS and network configurations for over 50 servers
 in production.

Low Latency Trading in a Cloud

Apr 2018 – Jul 2018

Worked as an integral team member developing and delivering an experimental low latency trading platform in the cloud (AWS, Azure and Oracle) ¹. Specific achievements included fine tuning the implementation and usage of the LMAX Disruptor pattern to maximize performance whilst executing in a virtual environment and advanced tuning of the G1GC garbage collector to significantly reduce jitter within the overall architecture.

Tatiana Didik 1/2

JENKINS / Sonar-Gerrit Plugin / Open-Source

2015 - 2017

Developed, documented and maintained a plugin for Jenkins², allowing to post SonarQube report data as a Gerrit review. It is currently installed in more than 1800 Jenkins instances³ and used in software development projects worldwide.

MAGENTA TECHNOLOGY / Echo / Software Engineer / Full Time

May 2010 - Jun 2014

Project: **Echo**⁴ is a Microsoft Gold Partner award winning ⁵ taxi dispatch enterprise software written in Java. The project is managed with Apache Maven, is based on relational database (MS SQL), accessed with Hibernate JPA via JBoss application server. Inventory used on this project includes JIRA as bug-tracking system, SVN for version control, TeamCity for continuous integration process. All the above were used on daily basis.

- ✓ Implemented software modules in accordance with functional specifications: fully configurable driver salary calculation, reporting and processing module; dynamic delay calculation⁶ as a part of the award-winning scheduling and auto-allocating features; framework for integration with external taxi aggregators (composing about 20% of corporate bookings⁷ in total) along with integration⁸ with One Transport taxi consolidator (now supplying businesses powered by Echo with thousands of cars monthly;
- ✓ Participated hands-on in functional specification design; contributed into system redesign allowing partnering companies such as greentomatocars and Trident Niven to share their resources and employees. This partnership allowed the companies to decrease by 13% the out-sourcing of spilling-over bookings;
- ✓ Was responsible for supporting and improving of a custom Java Swing UI framework allowing to generate UI components from xml files. Implemented a mechanism of editable fields highlighting in accordance with validation needs. Developed automated performance tests using TestComplete allowing to locate UI memory leaks and initiate heap dump when necessary. Performed detailed heap dump analysis with JProfiler, implemented a fix destroying circular links, preventing Java garbage collector from reclaiming unused objects. As a result, RAM allocation by the application has reduced dramatically.
- ✓ Participated in bugfixing, troubleshooting, maintenance and technical support of previously developed modules.

SSAU / Course Project

Sep 2011 - Jun 2012

Development of an algorythm of project time costs estimation

Design and development of a time management tool allowing to calculate estimated time costs for a complicated task set using UML for visualization, probability laws for estimation and a neural network for the process emulation.

Education

SAMARA STATE AEROSPACE UNIVERSITY / Samara, Russia Applied mathematics & informatics BS & MS

MS <u>2010 – 2012</u> BS <u>2006 – 2010</u>

- Discrete Math Math Statistics and Probability Theory Math Analysis Algebraic Structures ●
- Computer Telecommunications Parallel Computation and Programming Numerical Methods
 - Distributed DB and Expert Systems
 Math Modeling
 Math Methods of Cryptography

Tatiana Didik 2/2

¹ BJSS / LLT: https://www.bjss.com/high-frequency-low-latency-trading-in-the-public-cloud-the-time-is-now/

² Jenkins is the leading open source automation server for continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) https://jenkins.io/

³ Sonar-Gerrit plugin webpage is https://plugins.jenkins.io/sonar-gerrit, current installations statistics shown on http://stats.jenkins.io/plugin-installation-trend/sonar-gerrit.stats.json, the number is as of May 2019

⁴ Magenta / Echo: project web page: https://magenta-technology.com/echo

⁵ Magenta / Echo: Microsoft Gold Partner award news: https://magenta-technology.com/blog/2016/08/08/magenta-technology-gets-microsoft-gold-for-echo-taxi-and-private-hire-dispatch-software

⁶ Magenta / Echo: dynamic delays are mentioned in https://youtu.be/gqUy4VIYqoI?t=224 and explained in https://magenta-technology.com/blog/2016/09/12/are-all-apps-really-equal

⁷ Magenta / Echo: Booking sources statistics: https://magenta-technology.com/echo#corporate

⁸ Magenta / Echo: integration details: https://magenta-technology.com/echo#integration and https://m

⁹ Magenta / Echo: Two of Transdev's businesses (greentomatocars and Trident Niven) collaborate with empowerment of shared application instance https://magenta-technology.com/blog/2014/09/10/trident-niven-improves-efficiency-and-reduces-communication-traffic-by-60-with-magentas-taxi-dispatch-and-private-hire-software